{
    "id": "6907956da63d4827819adb383338c92e",
    "title": "Gap Filling Grammar Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I prefer riding my bicycle ………………………. driving the car.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "over",
                "to",
                "than"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "737859e8a54e4cc7b9161b24a07ec713"
        },
        {
            "question": "She enjoys ……………………………. time in her garden.",
            "description": "Enjoy should be followed by an ing form, not an infinitive.",
            "answers": [
                "spending",
                "to spend",
                "to spending"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "fbecd37b93ce44279afb9569653dacc7"
        },
        {
            "question": "I am not used to …………………………… alone.",
            "description": "The to in used to is a preposition. Use an ing form after a preposition. ",
            "answers": [
                "live",
                "living",
                "lived"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "321a075d8d204de5aa7337a7f82c3ec1"
        },
        {
            "question": "Would you mind ……………………………. for a minute?",
            "description": "Use an ing form after mind. ",
            "answers": [
                "to wait",
                "waiting",
                "wait"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "bb3c30ccdb62469abb39906fb5d1173e"
        },
        {
            "question": "That resort ………………………………… be a palace.",
            "description": "Used to can indicate past states. Would cannot be used to express this idea. ",
            "answers": [
                "used to",
                "would"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "0709ca801d254c349ca78e5c2839e609"
        },
        {
            "question": "I still remember ………………….. her for the first time.",
            "description": "When the reference is to past time, use an ing form after remember. ",
            "answers": [
                "meeting",
                "to meet",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "9cd93540930e41c9a15cc192ed4fab89"
        },
        {
            "question": "I would rather you ………………………….. me alone.",
            "description": "Use a past verb after would rather to refer to the present. ",
            "answers": [
                "leave",
                "left",
                "have left"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "63ed18c184d64b659362337dcddb0e93"
        },
        {
            "question": "It is high time you ……………………………. a job.",
            "description": "Use a past tense after high time to refer to the present.",
            "answers": [
                "find",
                "found",
                "have found"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "30a452db77044039bcff318b6a5cde09"
        },
        {
            "question": "I forgot …………………… him on his birthday.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "wishing",
                "to wish",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "f438c713d6134396bdf4c0bfe3cb2c65"
        },
        {
            "question": "I asked her ………………………………. she was interested.",
            "description": "Either if or whether can be used to introduce an Yes/No question. ",
            "answers": [
                "if",
                "whether",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "3d360c33079f45f0b8fd70fbbf61994f"
        },
        {
            "question": "Let him ................................ if he wants to.",
            "description": "Let is followed by an infinitive without to.",
            "answers": [
                "go",
                "to go",
                "going"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "ea24964befb948b3833ad6563d4d716c"
        },
        {
            "question": "I am ……………………………….. a call from my brother.",
            "description": "It should be I am expecting a call from my brother or I am waiting for a call from my brother. ",
            "answers": [
                "expecting",
                "expecting for",
                "waiting"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "eecef857461a4abfb68b997a881d6898"
        }
    ]
}